

Dubai UAE • 00971502587765 • Zuheir_khalek@hotmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Serviced-focused General Manager dedicated to giving every customer positive experiences to promote loyalty and repeat business.

Orchestrate optimal resource utilization to handle expected operational needs. Sales leader with sound judgment, good planning abilities and interpersonal communication strengths.

EDUCATION

AAS: Hotel, Restaurant and Institutional Management, 1992 Northern Virginia Community College, Annandale Virginia

SKILLS

- Relationship building
- Budgeting
- Staff training/development
- Deadline-oriented
- Operations management

WORK HISTORY

General Manager, 04/2017 to 05/2021 **Nassima Tower, Dubai UAE**

- Drove year-over-year business growth while leading operations, strategic vision and long-range planning.
- Delivered business strategy and developed systems and procedures to improve operational quality and team efficiency
- Enhanced operational efficiency and productivity by managing budgets.

General Manager, 01/2014 to 03/2017 **Radisson Blu Fujairah**

- Leading and managing the operations.
- The property is known for uncompromising quality in all services including Food and Beverage standards combined with world class accommodation and leisure facilities.
- Evaluated suppliers by assessing quality, timeliness and compliance of deliveries to maintain tight cost controls and maximize business operational efficiency.
- Organized budgets, oversaw P&Ls and achieved margin targets consistently to stay on track with growth plans.

Owner Representative (Asset Manager), 05/2011 to 12/2014 Acico Group, Acico Hotels Dubai UAE

 Directly over see the Three Properties owned Acico Hotels and Managed by Rezidor Hotel (Nassima Royal Dubai, Radisson Blu Fujairah and Nassima Tower Hotel Apartment).

Executive Assistant Manager, 05/2005 to 05/2011 **The Palms Beach Hotel and Spa Safat Kuwait**

- Direct and control the daily operation with the executive chef, front office and executive housekeeper department, including the weekly meeting with the sales team for upcoming booking and future business development for the resort.
- Modernized and improved operational procedures to increase efficiency and profitability while tightly controlling costs such as labor and preventing waste.
- Developed and implemented high-quality work environment as measured through employee satisfaction ratings.

Director of Operation, 03/2001 to 02/2005 **Coral Beach Resort** - Sharjah, United Arab Emirates, United Arab Emirates

Director of Room Service, 06/1999 to 11/2000

Bally's Casino and Resort (Hilton Hotels)

Las Vegas, Nevada USA

Director of Food & Beverage, 11/1998 to 06/1999 **Garden City Hotel, Intercontinental Global partner Hotel** -Long Island, New York

Assistant Director of Food & Beverage, 04/1993 to 11/1998 Hilton New York & Tower, Manhattan - New York, New York

Banquet Service Manager, 01/1992 to 03/1993 Hilton New York & Tower, Manhattan – New York New York

Executive Steward, 03/1991 to 12/1992

Hilton New York & Tower, Manhattan – New York New York

Restaurant Manager, 01/1989 to 01/1992 **Sir Walter Raleigh Inn** - Falls Church, Virginia

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native language

English:

Proficient